Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Papers
1862-1942
Mss.B.B61
American Philosophical Society
59.0 Linear feet
During the half century leading up to the Second World War, Franz Boas helped to define academic anthropology in the United States. Trained as a geographer at the University of Heidelberg, Boas worked initially on the Inuit of Baffin Island and subsequently on the cultures of the Indians of the Northwest Pacific Coast, becoming a leading figure in American anthropology by the first decade of the twentieth century. As Professor of Anthropology at Columbia University, Boas made significant theoretical contributions to ethnology, linguistics, and physical anthropology, helping to ingrain the four fields approach in his discipline and introducing the concept of cultural relativism into wide currency. He was, as well, a committed Socialist and an ardent opponent of both racism and fascism. This collection includes correspondence that Boas carried on with his colleagues in anthropology, as well as with those in the other social sciences and sciences. This correspondence is rich as a source for twentieth-century historians interested in "radical" social causes, since Boas was a socialist and an outspoken voice for progressive social causes.
59 lin. feet
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Biographical/Historical note
Born in Minden, Germany, on July 8, 1858, the anthropologist Franz Boas was the son of the merchant Meier Boas and his wife, Sophie Meyer. Raised in the radical and tradition of German Judaism, Franz's youth was steeped in politically liberal beliefs and a largely secular outlook that he carried with him from university through his emigration to the United States.
At the universities of Heidelberg and Bonn, Boas studied physics and geography before completing a doctorate in physical geography at Kiel in 1881. Intending on testing then-current theories of environmental determinism, he signed on to an anthropological expedition to Baffin Island in 1883-1884, expecting that he would document the close adaptative fit of Central Eskimo cultures to their extreme climate. His experiences in the arctic, however, led him to the contrary conclusion: that social traditions, not environmental, exerted a dominant influence over human societies, and from this point onward, he was led to pursue the cultural over than physical dimensions of humanity.
Although he returned to Berlin after the expedition, Boas emigrated to the United States in 1885 to assume an editorial position with the journal Science, hoping to use it as a stepping-stone to an academic appointment. In 1886, he embarked upon a second major field excursion into what would become his most famous ethnographic project, working among the Kwakiutl (Kwakwaka'wakw) Indians of the Northwest Coast, after which he secured his first academic position in 1889, at Clark University in Worcester, Mass. After three years at Clark and a failed appointment at the Field Museum in Chicago in 1892 (during which he played a part in organizing the anthropological exhibits for the Columbian World's Fair), Boas moved to New York City.
The restless activity of Boas's early years slowed in New York. Hired by the American Museum of Natural History (1895-1905), which became the recipient of the amazingly rich anthropological collections he accumulated on the Northwest Coast, Boas began to teach classes at Columbia University in 1896, where three years later he was appointed Professor of Anthropology. For the next 37 years, Boas ruled the anthropological roost at Columbia, accruing unprecedented power in his discipline, wielding grants, recommendations, and appointments with remarkable dexterity, and collecting about him a remarkable group of younger scholars as students and colleagues.
Distancing himself from some of the main currents of contemporary anthropological thought in the United States, and particularly from the evolutionist assumptions that riddled the discipline, Boas championed an anthropology that viewed human cultures as shaped more by historical "tradition" than biological propensity. Claiming to resist any overarching, synthetic theories of human relations, and particularly evolutionary theories of sociocultural development, Boas laid the theoretical groundwork for what became modern cultural relativism. In the process, he helped to clarify the demarcation between the concepts of culture and race and its expression in the divergence of the four fields in anthropology -- linguistics, ethnography, physical anthropology, and archaeology.
Boas's relatively few forays into physical anthropology included a pioneering anthropometric study in 1910-1911, demonstrating that the alleged mental and physical inferiority of immigrants disappeared statistically by the second generation. Opposed to immigration quotas and disdainful of the claims to science used to justify them, Boas was a consistent, strident opponent of racial determinism in intellect or behavior. A committed, politically active Socialist, he was frequently an outspoken critic of American policy. During the First World War, he spoke out against the treatment of German Americans and "enemy aliens" -- to the point of putting himself at risk -- and the rise of the Nazi party in Germany proved an even greater crusade. Despite his age, Boas took an active role in the anti-fascist struggle in the United States and was involved with numerous committees to assist refugee scholars. He was equally ardent in his efforts to criticize racial and ethnic bigotry in the United States.
As a mentor, Boas had a reputation of being directive, at times overbearing, and at the same time of doing too little to prepare his students for the rigors of fieldwork. The extraordinary number of students coming out of Columbia under his care, however, has arguably done as much to extend the Boasian approach than Boas's own writing. Margaret Mead, Ruth Benedict, Elsie Clews Parsons, Alfred Kroeber, Frank Speck, Edward Sapir, Zora Neale Hurston, Ella Deloria, Melville Herskovits, Leslie Spier, Paul Radin, and Ashley Montagu are all students of Boas. Many continued in the same intellectual stream, some diverged, yet all bore traces of Boas's influence. He left a mark as well on the institutions of the discipline, as one of the founders of the American Anthropological Association and of the International Journal of American Linguistics.
Scope and Contents note
The Boas Collections at the APS are the key resource for documenting the transformations in American ethnography, linguistics, and physical anthropology in the period between the 1880s and 1940s. The Boas Papers (Mss B B61) consist of the main body of Franz Boas's professional correspondence, including particularly extensive and important correspondence with Edward Sapir, Gladys Reichard, Elsie Parsons, Leo Frachtenburg, John Alden Mason, M. J. McGee, Frederick W. Hodge, Alfred Kroeber, George Hunt, and Alfred M. Tozzer, and material relating to Boas's involvement in professional and other organizations. This collection provides richly detailed coverage of every facet of Boas's career from the time of his emigration to America in the mid-1880s until his death in 1940, shedding light on the development of ethnography, anthropological linguistics, and anthropological approaches to archaeology. His correspondence was highly diverse, including not only his fellow anthropologists, but geneticists, evolutionary biologists, social scientists, and social activists.
The Boas collections are also a rich resource for historians interested in "radical" social causes in the twentieth-century through Boas's participation in socialist political circles and progressive social movements. There is significant material on the Germanistic Society of America and for German National Socialism and the expulsion of European scholars, as well as the efforts to reestablish them in British and American institutions.
This collection also contains photographs of Boas and members of his family from his childhood to the time of his death. Links to the digital versions of the pages are included in the inventory. You may also view a gallery of all images here.
Native American Images note: Nearly 3,000 sketches, albumen prints, black and white silver gelatin photographs, photomechanical prints, postcards, and maps of Baffinland Inuit and Northwest Coast Kwakiutl (Kwakwaka’wakw). Taken and drawn by Boas during his Northern Canadian expeditions of 1883-84 and 1886, images include native clothing, dwellings, totem figures, tools and kayaks. Of note, hand-drawn maps of Inuit tribal territories. Includes images sent to Boas from anthropologist John Alden Mason (Mayan), Amelia Susman and William Beynon (Tsimshian) of sculptures, carvings, and totems. Sketches are in the correspondence and field notebook series of B B61; B B61p; B B61.ru; B B61.5. The finding aid contains an inventory of all photographs housed in the Photograph Collection and on Film 1427. See also the American Council of Learned Society papers (497.3 B63c) for more Native American images by Boas.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Helene Boas Yampolsky, 1961-1962; and Dr. Cecil Yampolsky, 1964, with many later additions from Norman F. Boas.
Separated Materials note
Photographs have been separated for storage with the library's photographic collection.
Other Finding Aids note
This collection is thoroughly inventoried in Franziska Boas, Guide to the Microfilm Collection of the Professional Papers of Franz Boas (Wilmington, Del.: Scholarly Resources, 1972), 2 vols. This guide forms the basis of the inventory below.
Materials relating to Boas' research on American Indians is indexed in great detail in the online Daythal Kendall Guide to Native American Collections at the American Philosophical Society.
Bibliography
Rohner, Ronald P., ed., The Ethnography of Franz Boas: Letters and Diaries of Franz Boas, Written on the Northwest Coast from 1886 to 1931 (Chicago: Univ. of Chicago, 1969). Call no.: B B61e.r
Stocking, George, ed., The Shaping of American Anthropology, 1883-1911: A Franz Boas Reader (N.Y.: Basic Books, 1974). Call no.: 572.081 B63s
Cole, Douglas, Franz Boas: The Early Years, 1859-1906 (Seattle: Univ. of Washington, 1999).
Boas, Franz, The Mind of Primitive Man (N.Y.: MacMillan, 1911). Call no.: 572 B63m
Boas, Franz, Ethnology of the Kwakiutl (Washington, D.C.:Government Printing Office, 1921). Call no.: 572.97 B63e
Boas, Franz, Primitive Art (Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard Univ. Press, 1927). Call no.: 571.7 B63p
Boas, Franz, ed., General Anthropology (Boston: D.C. Heath, 1938). Call no.: 572 B63g.r
Boas, Franz, Race, Language and Culture (N.Y.: MacMillan, 1940). Call no.: 572.081 B63r
Existence and Location of Copies note
This collection has been microfilmed (film 1308) in chronological order.
Reel 1 February 24, 1878-January 31, 1889
Reel 2 February 1, 1889-April 30, 1894
Reel 3 May 1, 1894-December 30, 1898
Reel 4 January 5, 1899-March 26, 1903
Reel 5 April 2, 1903-December 30, 1904
Reel 6 January 2, 1905-January 24, 1906
Reel 7 January 24, 1906-January 4, 1907
Reel 8 January 4, 1907 -December 10, 1907
Reel 9 December 11, 1907-December 4, 1908
Reel 10 December 5, 1908-November 30, 1909
Reel 11 December 1, 1909-February 17, 1911
Reel 12 February 17, 1911-September 12, 1912
Reel 13 September 13, 1912-June 14, 1913
Reel 14 June 11, 1913-February 20, 1914
Reel 15 February 20, 1914-April 16, 1915
Reel 16 April 16, 1915-October 15, 1916
Reel 17 October 16, 1916-May 31, 1917
Reel 18 June 1, 1917-March 31, 1918
Reel 19 April 1, 1918-April 2, 1919
Reel 20 April 3, 1919-February 19, 1920
Reel 21 February 19, 1920-July 31, 1920
Reel 22 August 1, 1920-November 26, 1920
Reel 23 November 26, 1920-December 29, 1922
Reel 24 January 9, 1923-February 29, 1924
Reel 25 March 1, 1924-April 13, 1925
Reel 26 April 13, 1925-April 12, 1926
Reel 27 April 13, 1926-March 21, 1927
Reel 28 April 4, 1927-January 16, 1928
Reel 29 January 17, 1928-January 14, 1929
Reel 30 January 15, 1929-October 29, 1929
Reel 31 November 1, 1929-September 15, 1930
Reel 32 September 16, 1930-May 11, 1931
Reel 33 May 12, 1931-January 15, 1932
Reel 34 January 16, 1932-February 27, 1933
Reel 35 March 7, 1933-November 6, 1933
Reel 36 November 7, 1933-August 10, 1934
Reel 37 August 11, 1934-September 6, 1935
Reel 38 September 8, 1935-June 14, 1936
Reel 39 June 15, 1936-April 23, 1937
Reel 40 April 24, 1937-March 7, 1938
Reel 41 March 8, 1938-February 18, 1939
Reel 42 February 19, 1939-January 11, 1940
Reel 43 January 12, 1940-February 10, 1941
Reel 44 February 10, 1941-May 3, 1943
African American History Note
This collection has the potential to be rich for students of attitudes toward race in the United States. Among the many topics covered are the study and teaching of anthropology, ethnography, linguistics, progressive social causes, and the expulsion of European scholars under German national socialism.
Physiology, Biochemistry, and Biophysics Note
Scholars of physiology, biochemistry, or biophysics may find the following items of interest:
Levene, P. A. (Phoebus Aaron), 1869-1940 Correspondence (3 items) 1921 English
Loeb, Jacques, 1859-1924 Correspondence (5 items) 1920 English
Related Archival Materials note
Other Franz Boas Collections
Franz Boas Professional Papers, ca. 1860-1942 (Mss B B61p)
View Collection
Boas Family Papers, 1862-1942 (Mss B B61f)
View Collection
Boas-Rukeyser Collection, 1869-1940 (Mss B B61ru)
View Collection
Franz Boas field notebooks and anthropometric data, ca. 1883-1912 (Mss B B61.5)
View Collection
The American Council of Learned Societies Committee on Native American Languages, Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics ( Mss 497.3.B63c) is a large collection of primary materials on Native American languages assembled, in part, under Boas's supervision, and including a large quantity of material written by Boas himself.
Boas appears as a correspondent in numerous APS collections, and in addition to its rich collections for the history of anthropology, the library houses the papers of several of Boas's former students and proteges, including Frank Speck ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 126), Elsie Clews Parsons ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 29), John Alden Mason ( Mss. B M384), Paul Radin ( Mss. 497.3 R114), and Ashley Montagu ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 109).
The APS also houses a microfilm (372.3, reel 1) of original materials in the Office of Anthropology Archives, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., relating to Boas's trips to Baffin Island (N.W.T.) and British Columbia, during which he studied and collected cultural materials, 1885-1909.
The papers of Boas's son Ernst Boas ( Mss. Ms. Coll. 10) are housed at the APS. A physician, Ernst Boas shared his father's liberal political outlook and activist social views.
Andrews, H.A.; Beckwith, Martha Warren, 1871-1959; Boas, Ernst P., (Ernst Philip), 1891-1955; Bogoras, Waldemar, 1865-1936; Bowditch, Charles P., (Charles Pickering), 1842-1921; Britton, Nathaniel Lord, 1859-1934; Bumpus, Hermon Carey, 1862-1943; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944; Chávez, Ezequiel Adeodato, 1868-1946; Crane, M. E.; Dixon, Roland Burrage, 1875-1934; Engerrand, George C., 1877-1961; Fackenthal, Frank Diehl, 1883-1968; Franchtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930; Germanistic Society of America; Gordon, George Byron, 1911-; Heye, George G., (George Gustav), 1874-1957; Hodge, Frederick Webb, 1864-1956; Holmes, William Henry, 1846-1933; Hrdlicka, Ales, 1869-1943; Jochelson, Waldemar, 1855-1937; Keppel, Frederick P., (Frederick Paul), 1875-1943; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960; Laufer, Berthold, 1874-1934; McGee, W. J., 1853-1912; Michelson, Truman, 1879-1938; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939; Sargent, H. E.; Seler, Eduard; Steinen, Karl von den, 1855-1929; Swanton, John Reed, 1873-1958; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922; Tozzer, Alfred M. -- (Alfred Marston), -- 1877-1954.; Wissler, Clark, 1870-1947; Woodbridge, Frederick James Eugene, 1867-1940; Albumen prints; Anthropologists -- United States.; Anthropology, ethnography, fieldwork; Anthropology--Research--United States; Anthropology--United States--History.; Anthropology--United States.; Arctic Indians; Cabinet cards; Ethnology--North America; Gelatin silver prints; Indians of North America--British Columbia; Indians of North America--Ethnology; Indians of North America--Languages; Indians of North America--Northwest Coast; Indians of North America--Nunavut; Inuit; Jewish scientists; Kwakiutl Indians; Maps; Negatives; Northwest Coast Indians; Photomechanical prints; Postcards; Race, race relations, racism; Refugees, Political; Scientists, Refugee; Sketches.; Social conditions, social advocacy, social reform; Socialists--United States; Tlingit Indians
- Series I. Correspondence, 1862-1942; 59 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Letters to Franz Boas, copies of his replies, and related papers. The collection includes family papers, diaries, and personal correspondence, but the majority of the items are professional letters pertaining to the following subjects: the development of anthropology in America as both a science and a profession; the founding and later activities of the International School of American Archaeology and Ethnology in Mexico; international meetings of anthropologists; the study of American Indian linguistics; the study of physical anthropology and of race; field work of students. The papers also deal with the advancement of science, academic freedom, and public and political activities of Boas.
  Due to the size of the collection, the content for Series I has been divided into multiple inventories. Please follow the links below to browse the contents.
  View correspondents beginning with:
  Correspondents A
  Correspondents B
  Correspondents C
  Correspondents D
  Correspondents E-G
  Correspondents H
  Correspondents I-K
  Correspondents L
  Correspondents M
  Correspondents N-Q
  Correspondents R
  Correspondents S
  Correspondents T-V
  Correspondents W-Z
- Series II. Graphics, 1869-1940
  - Franz Boas with Marie, Helene, and Ernst at piano., ca. 1900; 1.0 Photoprint(s) 20.5 x 25 cm.; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Franz Boas with wife Marie in study., ca. 1900; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Minden Views 5: Dom, Minden, ca. 1900; Size: 11 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount.
  - Minden Views 6: Market, Minden, ca. 1900; Size: 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount.; Goldstein, Emma
  - Minden Views 7: Old house am Domhof., ca. 1900; Size: 11.5 x 14 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11.5 x 14 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount.; Goldstein, Emma
  - Minden Views 8: Domhof, inn where students drank beer during vacations, ca. 1900; Size: 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount.; Goldstein, Emma
  - Minden Views 9: Rathaus, haus von Emilie Boas, aunt of Franz, ca. 1900; Size: 11 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount.; Goldstein, Emma
  - Minden Views 10: Old house, am Poos (Heinrich Weber store), ca. 1900; Size: 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount.; Goldstein, Emma
  - Minden Views 11: Old house, am Poos (Magazn building), ca. 1900; Size: 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11.5 x 15.5 cm., 15 x 18 cm. mount.; Goldstein, Emma
  - Cabin (Franz Boas') on the Germania., 1883; Size: 12 x 16 cm., 18 x 22 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 12 x 16 cm., 18 x 22 cm. mount.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Wilhelm Weike and wife Mathilde, c. 2 (reproduction), 1883; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 2 photoprints; 20.5 x 25 cm.; Wenzel, Theodor
    For original see image U5.1.18
  - Wilhelm Weike and wife Mathilde, c. 2 (reproduction)., 1883; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 20.5 x 25 cm.; Wenzel, Theodor
  - Franz Boas, "on board the Germania on trip to Arctic"., 1883-1884; Size: 14 x 20 cm., 20.5 x 20.5 cm. sheet., Format: 1 photoprint; 14 x 20 cm., 20.5 x 20.5 cm. sheet.
  - Franz Boas, "age 49.", ca. 1907; Size: 10 x 14.5 cm., 18 x 25 cm. sheet., Format: 1 photoprint; 10 x 14.5 cm., 18 x 25 cm. sheet.; Heliotype Co.
  - Franz Boas, portrait (profile)., ca. 1920; Size: 11 x 15.5 cm., 20 x 24 cm. mount., Format: 1 photoprint; 11 x 15.5 cm., 20 x 24 cm. mount.; Becker and Maass
  - Franz Boas, at desk, 3/4 view, 3/4 length, c. 1 (original)., ca. 1935; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Franz Boas at desk, 3/4 view, 3/4 length, c. 2 (reproduction)., ca. 1935; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Franz Boas, at desk, 3/4 view, 3/4 length, c. 3 (reproduction), ca. 1935; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Franz Boas, at desk in Grantwood, N.J., c. 1 (original)., ca. 1942; Size: 16.5 x 21.5 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 16.5 x 21.5 cm.
  - Franz Boas, at desk in Grantwood, N.J., c. 2 (reproduction), ca. 1942; Size: 20.5 x 25 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Americanist Congress, The Hague (probably 22nd), ca. 1926; Size: 23 x 17 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 23 x 17 cm.
  - Franz Boas at American Association for Advancement of Science as incoming president, with Thomas Hunt Morgan, outgoing president., 1931-1932; Size: 12.5 x 19.5 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 12.5 x 19.5 cm.
  - Meyer Boas, portrait, 3/4 view, with white hair and mustache. Note from researcher Julie Liss of Scripps College, 12/4/98 regarding misidentification as Jonas Meyer., ca. 1880; Size: 12 x 17 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 12 x 17 cm.; Becker and Maass
  - Sophie Boas, portrait, 3/4 view, with dark blouse, lace trim. Note from researcher Julie Liss of Scripps College, 12/4/98 regarding misidentification as Sophie Meyer., ca. 1880; Size: 12 x 17 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 12 x 17 cm.; Becker and Maass
  - Salomon Meyer, portrait, "Onkel Mons" (uncle of Franz Boas), brother of Sophie Boas., ca. 1885; Size: 17 x 19.5 cm., Format: 1 photoprint; 17 x 19.5 cm.
  - Nors Head von Lucken (?), no. 2, 1883; Size: 9 x 17 cm., 14 x 17 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 9 x 17 cm., 14 x 17 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Dunnet Head, von Nordgeschen, 27th Juni 1883, no. 3, Size: 8 x 16.5 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 8 x 16.5 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eisberg, 28th Juli 1883, no. II, no. 5, Size: 10 x 17 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 10 x 17 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eisberg, 28th Juli 1883, Size: 10 x 15.5 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 10 x 15.5 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Laftgrieglungen 2 August, Motlag (?), no. 12, 1883; Size: 8.5 x 14.5 c.m., 14 x 19 mount., Format: 1 drawing; 8.5 x 14.5 c.m., 14 x 19 mount.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eisberg, 29th Juli 1883, no. 8, Size: 8.5 x 13 cm., 14 x 19 cm. mount., Format: 1 drawing; 8.5 x 13 cm., 14 x 19 cm. mount.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eisberg, 28th Juli 1883, No. IIb (No. 6), Size: 10 x 15 cm., 14 x 19 cm. mount., Format: 1 drawing; 10 x 15 cm., 14 x 19 cm. mount.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eisberg, 28th Juli 1883, Size: 8.5 x 15.5 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 8.5 x 15.5 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eisberg, 28th Juli 1883, no. 10, Size: 10 x 17 cm., 12 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 10 x 17 cm., 12 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eis im Lufgriegelungen (?) am 30 Juli, no. 11, 1883; Size: 8.5 x 15 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 8.5 x 15 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942